Mobolanle (Bola) Adebesin

Burtonsville, MD · 240-605-8753 · bolaadebesin@gmail.com · https://github.com/MobolanleAdebesin

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a full stack developer with a background in science and research. While my approach to programming is both analytical and methodical, my passion for technology and discovery drives me to relentlessly pursue creative solutions to complex problems.

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, jQuery, React, MongoDB, Wireframing, Git, Github, APIs, AdobeXD, Storybook, Python, PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Software Engineering Student, Washington, DC Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Three-month, 500-hour full-time, full-stack program providing experience with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, React, Git, Github, APIs, and AdobeXD. Projects include:
- Fairy Tale Trivia The purpose of this project was to build and deploy an interactive online game.
 I used object-oriented programming and Document Object Model to create a minimum viable product in four days. Built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
 https://github.com/MobolanleAdebesin/trivia-game
- Bookpals The purpose of this project was to build a single page application with full CRUD functionality using a REST API built from scratch within one week. Users can add, update, delete, and view their favorite books. Built with MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, React, Node. js https://github.com/MobolanleAdebesin/bookpals-front-end
 https://github.com/MobolanleAdebesin/bookpals-back-end
- Component Library The purpose of this project was to create a library of components including buttons, thumbnails, checkboxes, and forms. Users have access to an array of components that can be reused and modified for various websites. Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Storybook.
 - https://github.com/MobolanleAdebesin/component-library

Johns Hopkins University, Research Assistant, Baltimore, MD

May 2016 - Jun 2017

- According to the American Diabetes Association, diagnosed diabetes/metabolic dysregulation costs the US \$327 billion annually.
- The study used genetically variant mice to investigate the role of neural cells in metabolic dysregulation. The results provide a basis for potentially preventing, or delaying the onset of metabolic dysregulation, thus saving billions of dollars for the US healthcare system.
- Experimental data and analyses resulted in a publication at bioRxiv, a free online archive and distribution services:
 - https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/637587v1.abstract

UMBC, Office Assistant, Baltimore, MD

Aug 2014 - May 2016

- Managed the front desk for a 16-faculty department responsible for 500 undergraduate and 90 graduate students.
- Generated monthly budget tracking system for 10-15 grants valued at 5K-20K each.
- Streamlined efficiency of the budget system by removing redundancies in calculations to better predict spending trends and retain annual grant funding.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Student, General Assembly, Washington, DC, Sep 2019 - Dec 2019 **MD/Ph.D. Candidate**, Vanderbilt University School of Medicine, Nashville, TN, Jun 2017 - Jul 2019 **BS in Biology,** University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD, Aug 2012 - Aug 2016